Contact

210.200.9660 (Mobile) cnlegalnurse@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ darlenenelsonrnnurseconsultant (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing
ENPC
Post Anesthesia Care

Darlene Nelson RN

Nurse Consultant at Expert Nurse Consultants. San Antonio, Texas

Summary

As a testifying expert and nurse consultant since 1998 I have become well skilled in assisting both Plaintiff and Defense attorneys with preparing medical malpractice cases throughout the phases of litigation. As a Nurse Consultant I will bring to your case a broad knowledge base supported by thirty years of practice as an emergency/critical care, pediatric, interventional radiology and neuro-radiology nurse. Twenty years of my experience, until 2011, was obtained at a San Antonio academic, Level I Trauma. Comprehensive Stroke and Cardiac Center. I am detailed orientated with a very strong work ethic and believe in getting the job done and getting it right. Attorney references are available that kindly attest to the fact that i will go the extra mile as a matter of course. And to my commitment to producing not only an excellent product but one that truly contributes to building a case of integrity and strength. I possess strong, professional and direct communication skills and am a team player, though able to work independently.

I continue to assist attorneys throughout the U.S. in preparing their medical malpractice cases. I provide reviews for merit, identification of deviations from the standard of care or adherence to the standard, creation of timelines and chronologies, referral of well vetted board certified nurse and physician experts, deposition summaries, drafting of requests for discovery and interrogatories, assistance at deposition and trial, research retrieval and other services. I am well familiar with many of the nations hospital systems and know where to look for evidence. My rates are very reasonable.

Experience

Expert Nurse Consultants
Professional Nurse Consultant
January 1998 - Present (22 years 7 months)

Please see below

Texas Travel Nurse
Staff RN ER
June 2017 - October 2017 (5 months)
Texas

Adult and pediatric Emergency and Trauma Nurse ER and Critical Care RN - Adult and Pediatric Emergency, Trauma May 2013 - June 2017 (4 years 2 months)

San Antonio Area, Texas

Full time staff and charge nurse in busy adult and pediatric emergency room of community Level IV hospital. Responsible for planning and implementing and supervising the plan of care for the sick and injured child and adult utilizing evidenced based practice.

Parkland Hospital 5001 - 10.000 employees. and other temporary prn assignments
Emergency Trauma Nurse - travel nurse
January 2012 - May 2013 (1 year 5 months)
Dallas, Texas

Temporary position as Emergency and Triage RN in one of the nations largest University based Level I Trauma Center.

Methodist Healthcare System Emergency RN January 2011 - December 2011 (1 year)

Emergency Center RN while contemporaneously working at University Health System Hospital.

University Health System

Adult and Pediatric Emergency Room, Trauma, Radiology Staff Nurse III

August 1992 - August 2011 (19 years 1 month)

Staff Nurse III in Level I academic regional referral center for children and adults. Employed in 50 bed emergency center for total of 19 continuous years. Also filled position of float nurse working in adult and pediatric areas, emergency and critical care. While working in emergency center worked as Staff Nurse III in Radiology and Angio-gram from 1999 until 2011. MAGNET champion and Chair/member of unit councils and several

MAGNET champion and Chair/member of unit councils and severa professional committes.

The University of British Columbia Canadian Emergency and Critical Care Nurse December 1987 - May 1992 (4 years 6 months)

Vancouver, Canada Area

Emergency room nurse in Canadian academic regional referral hospital for 5 years until relocated to San Antonio, Texas

Education

Emergency Nurses Association CEN, TNCC · (1994 - 2017)

CERTIFICATION IN EMERGENCY NURSING

CEN, Emergency Room/Trauma Nursing · (1998 - 2017)

American Heart Association
ACLS, PALS, NRP, STROKE CERTIFICATION, Heart and Stroke
Care · (1988 - 2017)

Douglas College School of Nursing

Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1985 - 1987)